Finding Aid for the Ferdinand Canning Scott Schiller Papers, ca. 1870-1940
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
- Manuscripts and Galleys of Articles, Speeches, and Symposia
  - Formalism in logic. Oxford. n.d., Mind, vol.22, N.S., no.86., 2 leaves. Galleys with holograph notes. (Box 4)
    Also: two copies of the offprint.
  - Gesta deorum, I, II, & III. (Box 4)
    - I. A story of the creation. n.p. n.d., 10 leaves. Holograph. (Box 4)
      Also: another draft, 12 leaves, holograph.
      Also: clipping [in Italian] from Leonardo, November 1904.
    - II. The making of hell. n.p. February 1905, Leonardo. Clipping. (Box 4)
    - III. The slaying of Baldur. n.p. n.d., 9 leaves. Holograph. (Box 4)
      Also: clipping from Leonardo, June-August 1905.
  - Goethe and the Faustian way of salvation. n.p. January 17, 1935., 21 leaves. Holograph. (Box 4)
    Also: 11 leaves, holograph, manuscript of radio talk; and 6 leaves, typescript, script for radio talk.
  - Has philosophy any message for the world? Oxford. n.d., 4 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
    Also: 15 leaves, typescript, with holograph corrections.
  - How far does science need determinism? n.p. n.d., 12 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
    Also: offprint from the Travaux du IXe Congrès International de Philosophie, Aout, 1937.
  - How is 'exactness' possible? Oxford. n.d., 11 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
    Also: 9 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections; and 3 leaves, galleys.
  - The humanistic view of life. n.p. May 13, 1935., 19 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
    Library lecture.
  - The import of propositions. A symposium by E.E. Constance Jones, Bernard Bosanquet, and FCS Schiller. n.p. 1915, Proceedings of the Aristotelian Society., 16 leaves. Proof, with Schiller's notes. (Box 5)
    Also: 3 copies of the offprint, one of which has corrections in Schiller's Holograph.
  - Infallibility and toleration. Oxford. 1908, Hibbert Journal., 4 leaves. Proof with holograph notes. (Box 5)
    Also: clipping from the Hibbert Journal.
  - Is absolute idealism solipsistic? Oxford. 1905., 6 leaves. Holograph, incomplete. (Box 5)
    Also: clipping from The Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods, February 15, 1906.
  - Is idealism incurably ambiguous? Los Angeles. n.d., Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods., 2 leaves. Galleys with holograph corrections. (Box 5)
  - Is the distinction between moral rightness and wrongness ultimate? Oxford. 1930., 3 leaves. Holograph, incomplete. (Box 5)
    Also: reprint, with holograph notes.
  - Kant's Critique of pure reason. n.p. n.d., 17 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
  - The ladies' Aristotle. n.p. n.d., Pelican Record., 2 leaves. Galleys with holograph corrections. (Box 5)
  - Latta answer. n.p. n.d., 7 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
  - The little seed (another version). n.p. November 14, 1903., 6 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
    Also: 4 leaves, typescript, with holograph notes. [cf. letters from Victoria Welby in 1903].
  - Logic for use. n.p. February 22, 1930., 4 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
    Speech made before the Saturday Lunch Club.
  - The logic of miracle. n.p. n.d., 3 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
  - The logic of science. Oxford. 1913, Science Progress., 4 leaves. Galleys with holograph corrections. (Box 5)
    Also: clipping.
  - The madness of the absolute. Oxford. 1907., 1 leaf. Galleys with holograph corrections. (Box 5)
    Also: clipping from the Journal of Philosophy, Psycholgy, and Scientific Methods, January 3, 1907.
  - Man's limitations or God's? n.p. August 7, 1931., 22 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
  - Maya the queen. n.p. n.d., 3 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
  - The meaning of 'meaning'. (Box 5)
    [Includes 3 articles of the same title]
    - Article #1: n.p. 1919., 12 leaves. Holograph. Incomplete. (Box 5)
      Also: 2 offprints and one clipping from Mind, vol.29, N.S., no.116.
    - Article #2: Oxford. 1920., 11 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
      Also: offprint from Mind, vol.30, N.S., no.118.
    - Article #3: Oxford. n.d., 3 leaves. Holograph. Incomplete. (Box 5)
      Also: offprint from Mind, vol.30, N.S., no.120.
  - The meaning of 'self'. Oxford. n.d., 6 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
    Also: 5 copies of the offprint from Mind, vol.31, N.S., no.122.
  - Metaphysical implications of evolution. n.p. n.d., 6 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
  - Methodological teleology. Oxford. n.d., Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods., 3 leaves. Galleys with holograph corrections. (Box 5)
  - Multi-valued logics--and others. n.p. 1934., 28 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
    Also: 23 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections.
    Also: offprint from Mind, vol.44, N.S., no.176.
  - Must empiricism be limited? n.p. 1936., 22 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
  - Must philosophers disagree? Symposium. n.p. n.d., 1 leaf. Holograph. Incomplete. (Box 5)
    Also: 16 leaves, typescript, with holograph corrections; and 16 leaves, carbon of typescript; and 5 leaves, galleys with holograph notes, incomplete, from the Proceedings of the Aristotelian Society in 1933.
  - Must philosophy be dull? n.p. 1936., 14 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
  - Must pragmatists disagree? n.p. n.d., 7 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
  - Mysticism versus intellectualism. n.p. 1913, Mind., 1 leaf. Galley with holograph notes. (Box 5)
    Also: 1 clipping and 2 copies of the offprint from Mind, vol.22, N.S., no.85.
  - Name or shame? A denominational treatise by a nominalist philosopher. n.p. n.d., 1 leaf. Holograph. (Box 5)
  - The nature and validity of formal logic. A symposium by A.C. Ewing, FCS Schiller, C.S. Mace, and Rex Knight. n.p. 1931, Aristotelian Society., 21 leaves. Galleys with holograph notes by Schiller. (Box 5)
  - New realism (old idealism). n.p. n.d., 8 leaves. Holograph. (Box 5)
  - On a transatlantic view of British pragmatism. (Box 5)
    See British exponents of pragmatism.
  - Oxford and the working man. n.p. 1913, Fortnightly Review., 13 leaves. Proof with holograph corrections. (Box 5)
    Also: another copy and 1 clipping.
  - Philosophic fables. n.p. n.d., 9 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
  - The place of metaphysics. Oxford. ca. 1920, Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods., 3 leaves. Galley with holograph corrections. (Box 6)
    Also: clipping from August 12, 1960.
  - Plato's Phaedo and the ancient hope of immortality. [2 versions.] n.p. November 11, 1934., 22 leaves. Holograph. 4 leaves, typescript. (Box 6)
  - Pluralism and the ideal of unity. n.p. n.d., 2 leaves. Holograph. Incomplete. (Box 6)
    Also: 11 leaves, typescript with holograph notes.
  - The possibility of a metaphysical system. A symposium. n.p. October 8, 1899., 10 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
  - The possibility of a United States of Europe. n.p. n.d., 10 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
    Radio talk.
  - Practicable eugenics in education. Oxford. May 24, 1912., 1 leaf. Holograph. Incomplete. (Box 6)
    Also: galley (summary?) and pamphlet.
  - A pragmatic babe in the wood. Oxford. 1907, Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods., 4 leaves. Galley. (Box 6)
    Also: 1 clipping from the issue of January 17, 1907.
  - The pragmatic value of a liberal education. n.p. ca. 1927., 4 leaves. Galley with holograph corrections. (Box 6)
    Also: 1 copy of the pamphlet, with holograph corrections. A lecture delivered in the library of the Department of Education at the University of Liverpool, 20 May, 1927.
  - Pragmatismo e Umanismo [in Italian]. n.p. n.d., 17 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 6)
  - Pragmatism, humanism, and religion. n.p. n.d., 1 leaf. Holograph. (Box 6)
    Also: 14 leaves, carbon of typescript with holograph corrections, dated 1929; and 3 copies of the reprint, subtitled Lecture delivered at Scripps College on Tuesday, May 19, 1929, from Scripps College Papers, no.1, Lectures in Philosophy.
  - The principles of symbolic logic. Los Angeles. n.d., 2 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
    Also: 1 leaf, galley with holograph corrections, from the Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods.
  - The problem of formal logic. Oxford. n.d., 8 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
  - The problem of meaning. Symposium by FCS Schiller, W.F.R. Hardie, and A.C. Ewing. n.p. n.d., 11 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
    Also: 11 leaves, typescript, dated 1927; and 10 leaves, holograph, unfinished, rejoinder by FCS Schiller; and For symposium on meaning, 6 leaves, Holograph.
  - Professor Perry's realism. Oxford. n.d., 22 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
    Also: clipping, incomplete, and 1 copy of the offprint from Mind, vol.23, N.S., no.91.
  - Professor Schiller's reply. n.p. n.d., 1 leaf. Typescript. (Box 6)
  - The progress of psychical research. n.p. January 1905, Fortnightly Review., 14 leaves. Proof. (Box 6)
  - The proof of idealism. (Box 6)
    See Dreams and idealism.
  - Prophecy and destiny. n.p. November 22, 1936., 16 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
  - Pseudo-problems. n.p. January 19, 1933., 17 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
  - Psychology and psychical research. Oxford. n.d., 14 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 6)
    Also Psychology and psychical research, a reply to Professor Münsterberg, 1 clipping and 2 copies of the offprint from the Proceedings of the Society for Psychical Research, July 1899.
  - The psychology of exams. Oxford. 1927., 25 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
    Also: preface, 1 leaf, holograph, added 1930, Los Angeles.
  - The psychology of 'ghosts'. n.p. July 29, 1928., 25 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
  - Der rationalistische Wahrheitsbegriff. Oxford. n.d., 7 leaves. Galley with holograph corrections. (Box 6)
    Also: 3 copies of the offprint from the Verhandlung des III Internationalen Kongresses für Philosophie, Heidelberg, 1908.
  - Reality, fact, and value. n.p. ca. 1921., 1 leaf. Proof with holograph corrections. (Box 6)
  - Russell's theory of truth. n.p. n.d., 2 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
  - The soul spectroscope. n.p. n.d., 4 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
  - Theory and practice. n.p. n.d., 27 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 6)
  - This world--and others? n.p. n.d., 13 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
  - Truthseekers and soothsayers. n.p. n.d., 15 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
    Also: 10 leaves, typescript.
  - The ultra-gothic Kant. (Box 6)
    See Kant's Critique of pure reason.
  - The unity of the universe. Oxford. n.d., 6 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
    Also: 3 copies of the offprint from Mind, vol.42, N.S., no.168.
  - 'Useless' knowledge. n.p. n.d., 3 leaves. Holograph. Incomplete. (Box 6)
    Also: 1 copy of the offprint from Mind, vol.11, N.S., no.42.
  - War prophecies. n.p. n.d., Journal of the Society for Psychical Research., 5 leaves. Galley with holograph corrections, incomplete. (Box 6)
    Also: 1 clipping.
  - What is philosophy? n.p. ca. 1932, the Aristotelian Society., 3 leaves. Galley with holograph corrections. (Box 6)
  - What is truth? n.p. n.d., 11 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
  - William James and the will to believe. Oxford. n.d., 5 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
  - William James, the maker of pragmatism. n.d., n.p., 24 leaves. Holograph. (Box 6)
  - The 'working' of 'truths'. Mind, vol.21, N.S., no.84., 1 clipping and 2 copies of the offprint. (Box 6)
    Also: The 'working' of truths and their 'criterion'. 1 leaf, typescript, incomplete; and one copy of the offprint from Mind, vol.22, N.S., no.88.
- Manuscripts and Proofs of Books and Articles Contributed to Books by FCS Schiller
  - Axioms as postulates. Published in Personal idealism; Philosphical essays..., edited by Henry Cecil Sturt, London. 1902, Macmillan., pp.49-144. Incomplete. (Box 7)
    Printed copy with copious holograph additions.
  - Axioms as postulates [German translation]. n.p. n.d., 5 leaves. Holograph. Incomplete. (Box 7)
  - Humanism; philosophical essays. London, Macmillan. 1903. xxvii, 289., [11]pp. Proof copy with copious notes and corrections by Schiller. (Box 7)
    Also: additional leaves.
  - Hypothesis. Published in Studies in the history and methods of science, vol.2, edited by Charles Joseph Singer. Oxford: the Clarendon Press, 1921., pp.414-446. Proof. (Box 7)
    With corrections by Schiller.
    Also: another copy and additional leaves.
  - Introduction. Published in Civilisation or Civilisations, by E.H. Goddard and P.A. Gibbons. New York: Boni and Liveright. 1926., 10 leaves (pp.v-iv). Proof with corrections by Schiller. (Box 7)
  - Introduction. Published in The survival of western culture, by Ralph Tyler Flewelling. New York: Harper & Brothers. 1943., 3 leaves. Holograph. (Box 7)
  - Riddles of the sphinx., pp.i-xii. (Box 7)
    Printed copy with holograph corrections for the second edition.
  - Scientific discovery and logical proof. Published in Studies in the history and methods of science, vol.1. Edited by Charles Joseph Singer. Oxford: the Clarendon Press. 1917., Proof copy with holograph corrections. pp.235-289. (Box 7)
  - Studies in humanism. London, Macmillan. 1907. xvii., 492pp. (Box 7)
    Proof copy with notes and corrections by Schiller. First Proof.
  - Untitled manuscript. n.p. n.d., 35 leaves. Holograph. (Box 7)
    Chapter 1: Introductory. Chapter 2: The nature of action.
- Manuscripts and Proofs of Miscellaneous Items by FCS Schiller
  - Articles for the Encyclopedia Britannica. (Box 7)
    - Automatism., 2 leaves. galleys with holograph corrections. (Box 7)
    - Hartman, Karl Robert Eduard von., 1 leaf. Proof. (Box 7)
    - Nietzsche, Friedrich Wilhelm., 1 leaf. Proof with holograph corrections. (Box 7)
    - Spencer, Herbert., 6 leaves. Proof with holograph corrections. (Box 7)
  - Letters to Editors
    - 1. To the editor of the Spectator. n.p. n.d., 2 leaves. Typescript. (Box 7)
    - 2. To the editor of the Oxford Magazine. Oxford. ca. 1890., 2 leaves. Holograph. Rough draft. (Box 7)
      Also: 2 leaves, Holograph.
  - List of the chief philosophic writings of FCS Schiller, M.A., D.Sc. n.p. ca. 1910., 3 leaves. Holograph. (Box 7)
  - Obituary of William James. n.p. 1910, Nature., 1 leaf. Galley. (Box 7)
  - Personal response to the questionnaire of the Society for Psychical Research on human sentiment regarding a future life. n.p. 1901., 1 leaf. Holograph. (Box 7)
    [For a copy of the questions, See Answers to the American Branch's questionnaire regarding human sentiment as to a future life, in the copies of printed articles].
  - Publications of FCS Schiller during his tenure of an Extraordinary Fellowship at Corpus Christi College. 1926-1933. n.p. n.d., 4 leaves. Holograph. (Box 7)
    Also: 2 leaves, typescript.
  - Reports on International Congresses of Philosophy. (Box 7)
    - The Prague Congress. Oxford. 1934., 3 leaves. Typescript. (Box 7)
    - Another congress of philosophers. n.p. n.d., 3 leaves. Proof. (Box 7)
    - A synod of sages. n.p. n.d., 2 leaves. Galley. (Box 7)
  - Séance with Eglinton. January 22, 1885. n.p., 1 leaf. Holograph. (Box 7)
- Miscellaneous and Unidentified Manuscripts by FCS Schiller
  - Untitled Manuscripts
    - 1. 8 leaves. n.p. n.d. Holograph. (Box 8)
    - 2. Comments by FCS Schiller. n.p. n.d., 3 leaves. Holograph. (Box 8)
    - 3. II. FCS Schiller. n.p. n.d., 3 leaves. Holograph. (Box 8)
  - Untitled German Manuscripts
    - 1. 5 leaves. Typescript with holograph additions. n.p. n.d. (Box 8)
    - 2. Fragments. v.p. v.d., 15 leaves. (Box 8)
  - Incomplete Manuscripts and Notes. v.p. v.d.
    - Analysis of Epy and Psychology., 5 leaves. Holograph. (Box 8)
    - Ancient statecraft and new democracies., 1 leaf. Holograph. (Box 8)
    - B's A & R., 2 leaves. Holograph. (Box 8)
    - Can the Lords be made a bulwark against revolution?, 2 leaves. Holograph. (Box 8)
    - Criticism of McTaggert., 2 leaves. Holograph. (Box 8)
    - Ethical theory and practice., 1 leaf. Holograph. (Box 8)
    - Free will., 1 leaf. Holograph. (Box 8)
    - Freedom in ethics., 1 leaf. Holograph. (Box 8)
    - Implication., 2 leaves. Holograph. (Box 8)
    - Michaelmas 1904, Mr. Schiller's Problems of modern logic., 1 leaf. Holograph. (Box 8)
    - Mr. Russell's analysis of mind., 1 leaf. Typescript. (Box 8)
    - Must philosophical language be ambiguous? (Box 8)
    - Notes on Calderwood and Green., 2 leaves. Holograph. (Box 8)
    - Notes on Faust., 4 leaves. Holograph. (Box 8)
    - Plato's theory of ideas., 2 leaves. Holograph. (Box 8)
    - Pragmatic logic: questions for discussion., 1 leaf. Typescript. (Box 8)
    - Psychology., 1 leaf. Holograph. (Box 8)
    - Reason, will, desire., 1 leaf. Holograph. (Box 8)
    - Virtue and habit., 2 leaves. Holograph. (Box 8)
  - Assorted notes. v.p. v.d., 50 leaves. Holograph. (Box 8)
  - Unidentified fragments of articles. n.p. n.d., 91 leaves. Holograph. (Box 8)
  - Fragments of galleys and proofs. n.p. n.d., 7 leaves. (Box 8)
- Courses, Lecture Series, Exams, and Syllabi by FCS Schiller
  - Courses:
    - Plato's Republic. n.p. n.d., 160 leaves. Holograph. Incomplete. Rough draft. (Box 9)
    - Plato's Republic. n.p. n.d., 317 leaves. Holograph. (Box 9)
    - Practical ethics. n.p. 1934., 203 leaves. Holograph. (Box 9)
      Also: analysis, 5 leaves, Holograph.
    - Pragmatism. 1933. n.p., 62 leaves. Holograph. (Box 9)
    - Pragmatism. 1934. n.p., 90 leaves. Holograph. (Box 9)
    - Theatetus. 1907, n.p., 64 leaves. Holograph. (Box 9)
  - Lecture Series:
    - Forum lectures. 1932. n.p., 1932. Notes., 1 leaf. Holograph. (Box 9)
      Some philosophic reflections on cosmic E_____ and man's place in nature.
      - 1. The metaphysics of change., 13 leaves. Typescript. (Box 9)
      - 2. The meaning of biological history., 13 leaves. Typescript. (Box 9)
      - 3. The development of man., 12 leaves. Typescript. (Box 9)
      - 4. Man's future on the earth., 11 leaves. Typescript. (Box 9)
    - Humanism. n.p. n.d. (Box 9)
      - 1. The place of humanism in the field of thought., 15 leaves. Holograph. (Box 9)
      - 2. Humanist logic and theory of knowledge., 14 leaves. Holograph. (Box 9)
      - 3. Humanist ethics., 14 leaves. Holograph. (Box 9)
      - 4. Humanism and the metaphysical problem., 12 leaves. Holograph. (Box 9)
  - Introductions, Syllabi, and Exams:
    - Logic seminar. 1930. n.p., 12 leaves. Holograph. (Box 9)
    - Ethics. 1930. n.p., 4 leaves. Holograph. Unfinished. (Box 9)
    - Syllabi. (Box 9)
      - Syllabus of lectures on teleology and evolution., 4 printed copies. (Box 9)
      - Syllabus of philosophy 100. n.p. 1932., 3 dittoed copies. (Box 9)
      - Tentative outline of logic. n.p. n.d., 1 leaf. Typescript. (Box 9)
    - Exams. v.p. v.d., 11 leaves. Holograph. (Box 9)
      Also: 10 leaves, typescript, and 2 leaves, printed.
    - Notes and Fragments:
      - Notes on Stout. n.p. 1900., 22 leaves. Holograph. (Box 9)
      - Philosophy of Plato. n.p. n.d., 45 leaves. Holograph. (Box 9)
      - Part 2--The psychology of cognition. n.p. n.d., 52 leaves. Holograph. Pages numbered 104-154. (Box 9)
- Books Reviewed by Schiller
  - Schiller, Ferdinand Canning Scott. Reviews of various books by various authors. v.p. v.d., 199 items. Holograph, typescript, galleys, and clippings. (Box 10)
    - Adams, G.P. Studies in the nature of truth. (Box 10)
    - Aliotta, Antonio. La reazione idealistica contro la scienza. (Box 10)
    - Ayer, Alfred J. Language, truth, and logic. (Box 10)
    - Baker, Rannie Belle. The concept of a limited God; a study in the philosophy of personalism. (Box 10)
    - Barthel, Ernst. Vorstellung und Denken, eine Kritik des pragmatischen Verstandes. (Box 10)
    - Baumgardt, David. Der Kampf um den Lebenssinn unter den Vor¨läufen der modernen Ethik. (Box 10)
    - Bentley, Arthur F. Behavior, knowledge, fact. (Box 10)
    - Bosanquet, Bernard. Three chapters on the nature of mind. (Box 10)
    - Bradley, F.H. The principles of logic. (Box 10)
    - Bridgman, P.W. The nature of physical theory. (Box 10)
    - Brightfield, Myron F. The issue in literary criticism. (Box 10)
    - Burke, John Butler. The emergence of life, being a treatise on mathematical philosophy and symbolic logic by which a new theory of space and time is evolved. (Box 10)
    - Campbell, Charles A. Scepticism and construction, Bradley's sceptical principle as the basis of constructive philosophy. (Box 10)
    - Carmichael, R.D. The logic of discovery. (Box 10)
    - Carnap, Rudolf. Le probleme de la logique de la science formelle et science du reel. (Box 10)
    - Carr-Saunders, A.M. The population problem, a study in human evolution. (Box 10)
    - Church, Ralph W. Hume's theory of the understanding. (Box 10)
    - Cinquieme Semaine Internationale de Synthese. Science et loi. (Box 10)
    - Clarke, Mary Evelyn. A study in the logic of value. (Box 10)
    - Coffey, P. Epistemology of the theory of knowledge: an introduction to general metaphysics. (Box 10)
    - Columbia University, Department of Philosophy, editor. Studies in the history of ideas. vol.1. (Box 10)
    - Columbia University, Department of Philosophy, editor. Studies in the history of ideas. vol.2. (Box 10)
      See Dewey, John, Nature and Experience.
    - Compton, Arthur H. The freedom of man. (Box 10)
    - Conger, George Perrigo. New views of evolution. (Box 10)
    - Coover, John Edgar. Experiments in psychical research, being the Leland Stanford Junior University's Psychical Research Monograph no.1. (Box 10)
    - Cooper, Lane. The rhetoric of Aristotle, an expanded translation with supplementary examples for students of composition and public speaking. (Box 10)
    - Cope, E.D. The primary factors of organic evolution. (Box 10)
    - Cornford, Francis Macdonald. Plato's theory of knowledge, the Theatetus and the Sophist of Plato translated with a running commentary. (Box 10)
    - Crozier, John Beattie. Last words on great issues. (Box 10)
    - Dewey, John. A common faith. (Box 10)
    - Dewey, John. Nature and experience. (Box 10)
    - Dewey, John. Philosophy and civilization. (Box 10)
    - Dickinson, G. Lowes. After two thousand years, a dialogues between Plato and a modern young man. (Box 10)
    - Dorsey, John Morris. The foundations of human nature, the study of the person. (Box 10)
    - Driesch, Hans. Psychical research, the science of the supernormal. (Box 10)
    - Dunne, J.W. An experiment with time. (Box 10)
    - du Prel, Carl. Die Entdeckung der Seele durch die Geheimwissenschaften. (Box 10)
    - Edgell, Beatrice. Theories of memory. (Box 10)
    - Elkin. Hume. (Box 10)
    - F., G.C. Studies in philosophy. (Box 10)
    - Fawcett, Edward Douglas. The world as imagination. (Box 10)
    - File, Werner. The platonic legend. (Box 10)
    - Flournoy, Th. Nouvelles observations sur un cas de somnambulisme avec glossolalie. (Box 10)
    - Flournoy, Th. La philosophie de William James. (Box 10)
    - Flournoy, Th. The philosophy of William James. (Box 10)
    - Förster-Nietzsche, Elizabeth. The young Nietzsche. (Box 10)
      See Nietzsche, Friedrich.
    - Ginsberg, Morris. Studies in sociology. (Box 10)
    - Gunn, J.A. Modern French philosophy. (Box 10)
    - Haldane, J.B.S. The causes of evolution. (Box 10)
    - Haserot, Francis S. Essays on the logic of being. (Box 10)
    - Helder, Jacob. Greatest thoughts on immortality. (Box 10)
    - Hobhouse, L.T. Development and purpose; an essay towards a philosophy of evolution. (Box 10)
    - Hocking, W.E. The spirit of world politics. (Box 10)
    - Hone, J.M. Bishop Berkeley, his life, writings, and philosophy. (Box 10)
    - Huxley, Julian S. What dare I think? the challenge of modern science to human action and belief. (Box 10)
    - Inge, William Ralph. God and the astronomers, containing the Warbarton Lectures. 1931-1933. (Box 10)
    - Jacks, L.P. The alchemy of thought. (Box 10)
    - Jacks, L.P. The faith of a worker. (Box 10)
    - Jacks, L.P. The inner sentinel, a study of ourselves. (Box 10)
    - Jaeger, Werner. Aristotle, fundamentals of the history of his development. (Box 10)